Justin Casler

Email: justinlcasler@gmail.com Phone: 617 981 2722 LinkedIn: LinkedIn.com Website: justincasler.com

Upcoming 2024 Computer Science and Physics graduate with a strong foundation in backend engineering and experience in object-oriented languages, database design, and data science. Quick to learn new technologies and excited to succeed as an intern software engineer.

Education

Wesleyan University 2020-2024

Bachelor of Arts, Overall GPA: 3.85/4.00, Middletown, CT

Newton South High School 2016 - 2020

Overall GPA: 3.94/4.00, Newton, MA

Work Experience

Privacy Tech Lab Middletown, CT

Software Engineer January 2022 to Present

- > Wrote insightful, performant backend code for Google Research Scholar award-winning privacy product
- > Successfully trained NLP model to over 90% accuracy on test data set by creating and annotating datasets and specifying hyperparameters to optimize learning
- > Effectively debugged front and backend code quantified by high ratings in our usability study

Wesleyan University

Middletown, CT

Course Assistant September 2021 to May 2022

- > Assisted students in debugging code and forming methodologies to attack a variety of problems
- > Aided teacher by grading 25+ programming assignments per week
- > Held out of class help sessions to review concepts with ~20 students every week and recieved positive review at the end of semesters via the students and teacher

Mathnasium Boston, MA

Tutor June 2019 to March 2021

- > Assisted 100+ elementary and middle school students to grasp math concepts
- > Made STEM more approachable and inspired confidence in young students by catering my teaching strategies
- > Coordinated meetings and schedules for tutors in training to ensure an organized development plan

Skills

Programming Languages: Python Java JavaScript SQL C C++

Libraries & Frameworks: Node React jQuery TensorFlow PyTorch Hugging Face

Interests

Hiking, puzzles, cooking, and board games